DAYS!
By the decision of Ying Zheng, the king that wished to unite all of China,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
天下統一の道を行く王 嬴政(えいせい)のもと
秦国(しんこく)は 隣国 魏(ぎ)への侵攻を開始した
the State of Qin began its invasion of the neighboring State of Wei.
Wang Ben, Meng Tian, and Xin.
王賁(おうほん) 蒙恬(もうてん) そして信(しん)
未来の大将軍たらんとする兵(つわもの)が―
Three soldiers wishing to become Great Generals are gathered here
今ここに集い
新しき時代を迎えようとしていた
trying to usher in a new age.
By the recommendation of State of Qin Supreme Commander Meng Ao,
秦国軍総大将 蒙驁(もうごう)将軍の
推挙により―
信は 臨時とはいえ
ついに千人将に昇格した
although it was temporary, Xin was finally promoted to being a Thousand-Man General.
But around that time, the legendary military commander, General Lian Po, left the State of Wei capital for the front lines.
だが そのころ
魏国の王都からは―
伝説の武将 廉頗(れんぱ)将軍が
前線に向かって出陣していた
The Night Before
the Start of the War
（渕(えん)）アア…
（信）ウハハハハッ！
さすがに壮観だな 渕さん
A great view, ain't it, Mr. Yuan?!
1,000人だぜ 1,000人！
（渕）え… ええ まあ…
There's a thousand men here! A thousand!
Ah, yes.
（尾平(びへい)）し… 信のヤツ
Geez, Xin's not intimidated at all with these thousand people in front of him!
この1,000人を前にしても
全く動じてねえ
（竜川(りゅうせん)）
すげえ　さすが俺らの隊長だ
Our captain sure is incredible.
（松左(しょうさ)）バカなだけだろう
He's just stupid.
But can he really speak well under these conditions?
（去亥(きょがい)）でも この状況で
あいつ うまく しゃべれんのか？
Look at these new 700 men.
（田永(でんえい)）
見ろよ　新しく加わった あの700人
騎兵もいるし
歩兵は全員 甲冑(かっちゅう)を着てる
There are mounted soldiers and all of the foot soldiers are wearing armor.
You can bet that that's a unit of nobles.
（松左）
ありゃ間違いなく士族の部隊だな
Do you think they'll be pissed about joining a band of peasant folk like us?
（去亥）俺らみてえな農民部隊に
くっつけられて―
頭に来てんじゃねえのか？
Uh, maybe.
（尾平）あ… ありえるな
We are 700 men of the former Guo Bei Unit!
（楚水(そすい)）元郭備(かくび)隊700名
信千人将に向かって―
Show Thousand-Man General Xin
a salute!
拝手！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
なっ…
（去亥）も… 元郭備隊？
F-Former Guo Bei Unit?!
（郭備）
貴士族なんかに負けるなよ 信
Let's not lose to any nobles or warrior class families, Xin!
Lord Guo Bei has been telling us of the Feixin Unit's exploits for quite some time.
飛信(ひしん)隊の活躍は―
以前より郭備さまが
我々に語っておられました
そこに加われることを
誇りに思います
We are proud to join you.
We intend to devote our lives to the Feixin Unit from this day forward,
今日より 我々は
飛信隊として命を懸ける所存ですが
but we hope you will forgive us for holding thoughts of our departed Lord Guo Bei in a corner of our hearts.
道半ばで倒れた郭備さまの思いも
胸の片隅に抱いて戦うことを―
お許しくだされ
Of course.
当然だ
What's your name?
あんた 名前は？
（楚水）元郭備隊副長の楚水です
I am Chu Shui, the Vice Captain of the Former Guo Bei Unit.
I am pleased to make your acquaintance.
以後 お見知りおきを
（信）分かった
Got it. So please be a Vice Captain here, too.
それじゃ 楚水
ここでも副長のひとりになってくれ
There's a whole lot I'd like you to teach me.
いろいろ
教えてもらいてえことがある
Yes, sir.
I'm totally glad to be fighting with the Guo Bei Unit as well!
（信）俺らも
郭備隊と一緒に戦えることを―
すげえ うれしく思う！
But like Vice Captain Chu Shui just said, starting now we're all part of the same Feixin Unit!
だが 楚水副長が今言ったように
これからは同じ飛信隊だ！
Now, it no longer matters if you're nobles or peasants!
ここでは 士族も農民も関係ねえ
Nor does it matter if you're veterans or newcomers!
古株も新参も関係ねえ
Just fight, carrying all the different things you bring with you!
みんなも いろんなもん
しょいこむだけ しょいこんで―
戦えばいい！
We will use all of that to become one mass that blows our enemies away!
俺たちは そうして
ひとつの でっけえ塊になって
敵をぶっ飛ばす！
Let's go, Feixin Unit!
いくぞ 飛信隊！ 狙うは敵将…
Our target is the head of the enemy general...
廉頗の首だー！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
General Lian Po!
Awesome!
すげえ… すげえぞ 信のヤツ！
That was incredible, Xin!
ああ 郭備隊が仲間になった！
Yeah. The Guo Bei Unit is part of us now!
One of the primary elements of a superior general is voice.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）優れた武将の
要素のひとつに“声”がある
To make an impassioned speech
that rouses the troop's morale.
弁を振るって
隊の士気を上げるためには―
言葉を乗せる声の力が
重要なのである
A voice which gives weight to one's words is vital.
Xin's voice was mysteriously quite effective.
そして 信の声は
不思議と よく通った
Xin's passion was always acutely conveyed to the listener.
聞き手には 信の声を通して
その情熱がヒシヒシと伝わっていた
With the Feixin Unit being reborn from a Thousand-Man General, this was a superb start.
千人隊となった新生飛信隊の
門出としては―
上々の滑り出しになったのである
そのころ 王都 咸陽(かんよう)には―
Meanwhile, the news of General Lian Po's sortie reached the royal capital of Xiangyang.
廉頗将軍出陣の知らせが
もたらされていた
Changpingjun, why do you not send reinforcements?
（呂不韋(りょふい)）
昌平君(しょうへいくん) なぜ援軍を送らぬ？
Our enemy is the Lian Po.
敵は あの廉頗だぞ
I had already hypothesized that Lian Po may emerge, as a precaution.
（昌平君）廉頗が出てくるのは
念のため 想定していました
The Meng Ao Army has the fighting power to combat it.
（昌平君）蒙驁軍には それに
対応する戦力は持たせてあります
Additionally, we do not have the luxury of being able to send reinforcements.
それに
援軍を送るほど余裕はありません
Qin
Shanyang
The State of Qin must make a foothold if we want to progress into the center of Shanyang.
山陽(さんよう)は
秦国が中央に進出するために―
足がかりとして
必ず取らねばならない場所です
しかし 山陽を攻めれば
魏国だけでなく 韓(かん)…
But if we attack Shanyang, it will not only be the State of Wei,
Wei
Shanyang
Han
Qin
Chu
but Han and the great southern State of Chu are likely to act.
そして 南の大国 楚(そ)も
動きだすはずです
Chu's goal will also be to prevent the State of Qin from capturing Shanyang.
楚の目的もまた
秦国に山陽を取らせぬこと
That is simply how big a barrier this land of Shanyang has become for expanding the State of Qin's territory.
それほどに
この山陽という土地は―
秦国の領土拡大の
大きな障壁となっているのです
But it can't be done.
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）だが ムリじゃ
（文官たち）ハッ…
According to the report, General Meng Ao has 140,000, and Lian Po's opposing State of Wei Army also has 140,000.
（昌文君）報告によれば―
蒙驁軍14万に対し
廉頗の魏国軍も14万
With armies of the same scale, Lian Po cannot be beaten.
同規模の軍では
あの廉頗には勝てはせぬ
You do not understand just how fearsome Lian Po's supreme command is.
総司令は
廉頗の恐ろしさが分かっていない
We are aware it is somewhat unreasonable.
多少のムリは承知のうえ
Shanyang
But now that we have an alliance with the State of Zhao, this is our only chance.
趙国(ちょうこく)との同盟がある今しかないのだ
We must take Shanyang in this war at all cost.
（政）なんとしても
この戦で山陽を取らねばならん
If the State of Qin seriously intends to conquer China!
秦国が本気で中華を狙うのならな
My lord,
（李斯(りし)）
殿　大王のあの目は 一体…
just what were those eyes his majesty had?
Those are eyes that know everything...
（呂不韋）
あれは全てを知っておるな
They know, but did not say anything...
知っていて
あえて何も言わなかった
Those eyes
あの目は
わしや太后を見てはおらぬ
are not looking at me nor the Queen Dowager...
フッ… まったく
Honestly...
Yes... My goal is the uniting of China.
そうだ 俺が目指すのは
中華の統一
Until then, I cannot stand still.
それまでは
立ち止まるわけには いかんのだ
Whether my enemy is a chancellor or the greatest general under the heavens!
相手が丞相(じょうしょう)であろうと
天下の大将軍であろうと…
Xin...
信…
フッ… 約束をしたのは俺のほうだ
I'm the one that made a promise.
I'm not going to lose either, Xin!
俺も負けんぞ 信
At the end of this day, the strife within the royal palace calms.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）この日を境に
王宮内の争いは沈静化した
It is quite temporary,
あくまで一時的ではあるが―
but for now, the State of Qin is united in its attack on Shanyang.
秦国は 山陽攻略に向けて
ひとつに まとまったのである
Hey, Thousand-Man General Meng Tian!
（信）よう！ 蒙恬千人将！
（蒙恬）
やあ！ これはこれは 信千人将
Oh, well if it isn't Thousand-Man General Xin?
そういや 飛信隊には
郭備隊が入ったんだって？
That reminds me, is it true that the Guo Bei Unit joined the Feixin Unit?
Yeah, they did.
ああ まあな
…て ズルイな　すげえ強(つえ)え助っ人(と)
Aw, that's no fair.
You got such incredibly strong new helpers!
（信）ズルくねえよ 全然
It's totally fair!
その様子じゃ 最初の挨拶は
うまくいったみたいだな
Given your mood, it sounds like your first meeting went well.
（信）
おうよ！ お前は どうだったよ？
Yeah. How'd yours go?
楽勝　だって お坊ちゃんだからね
An easy victory.
I'm a revered young master after all.
黙ってても み～んな頭下げるし
Everyone would bow their heads even if I didn't say anything.
そうだった…
Oh, right.
This guy is Meng Wu's son and General Meng Ao's grandson.
こいつは
蒙武(もうぶ)の子供で 蒙驁将軍の孫だった
But man, there's no resemblance between them at all.
しかし 似てねえ親子だな
（蒙恬）臨時的ではあるけど
この戦じゃ 紛れもなく千人将だ
It may just be temporary, but in this war you are unmistakably a Thousand-Man General.
It sure feels like when you're leading a thousand men,
さすがに1,000人も兵を抱えると
you're really one of the comrades to the military commanders, huh?
武将の
仲間入りしたって感じがするな
Yeah, I guess so.
ああ そうだな
Hey, Thousand-Man General Xin!
（蒙恬）よう 信千人将！
（信）よう 蒙恬千人将！
Hey, Thousand-Man General Meng Tian!
（信･蒙恬）ハハハハッ！
（尾平）何やってんだ あいつら…
What are those guys doing?
You two are getting too enthused.
（王賁）浮かれ過ぎだ お前たちは
（信･蒙恬）うん？
Oh, what do we have here?
おお これはこれは 王賁千人将！
Thousand-Man General Wang Ben!
よう 王賁千人将！
Hey, Thousand-Man General Wang Ben!
Pipe down!
（王賁）やかましい
（王賁）お前たちは 自分の
置かれた状況が分かっていない
You two do not understand the position you've been placed in.
Just as General Meng Ao said,
（王賁）
蒙驁将軍が言ったように―
軍内には 我ら３人の昇格を
妬む者が大勢いる
there are a great many people in the army that are jealous that we were promoted.
Well, I can see how it would be less than entertaining for those that have their sights on the top. We're so young after all.
まあ
上を狙ってる人たちにとっては―
面白くないからね　若造だし
フン… 関係ねえ！
That doesn't mean a thing!
The problem is that such people exist in the upper echelons as well.
（王賁）問題は そういう連中が
上層部にも存在するということだ
If we lose in this war, we will likely be treated like war criminals.
この戦に敗れれば―
恐らく
俺たちは戦犯扱いを受けるぞ
（信）なっ…
（蒙恬）だろうね
Yeah, probably.
If you get it, then quit fooling around and focus on your tactics as Thousand-Man Generals.
分かったら ヘラついてないで
千人隊の戦術でも考えておけ
A Thousand-Man Unit is already a military force large enough to change the state of a war.
千人隊は もはや
戦局を変えることができる軍隊だ
A military force that can change the state of a war...
戦局を変える軍隊…
ケッ！ 偉そうに あいつ！
Look at him, acting all high and mighty....
なんで いつもピリピリしてんだ？
バ～カ！
Why's he always so uptight? Geez...
ハハハッ… そう言うなよ
Don't say that.
名門に生まれた重責ってのも
あるんだよ
Even those born to noble families have heavy responsibilities.
それが あまりに重いと
俺みたいな適当人間になるか―
And if it's too heavy, you end up a devil-may-care type like me
or a tight-ass like him.
あいつみたいに
カッチリ人間になるのさ
特に 偉大すぎる父親を持つとな
（信）えっ？
Especially the types with the really prominent fathers.
The newly reorganized Meng Ao Army and the armies of the two Vice Generals are moving in pace together
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
軍の再編成を終えた蒙驁軍は―
２人の副将の軍と足並みをそろえ
最終目的地 山陽の地へと
近づいていた
and drawing on their final objective, Shanyang.
Meanwhile, in a castle of a state neighboring the State of Wei, Huangan in the State of Zhao...
そのころ 魏国に隣接する趙国の城
環甘(かんかん)では…
Urgent report!
（伝者Ａ）急報！
秦国軍副将により 山非城(さんぴじょう) 陥落！
Shanfei Castle has been captured by a State of Qin Army Vice General!
What?!
（文官）なんだと？
（文官）早すぎる…
It's far too soon...
（文官）
これで いくつ目だ？
How many does this one make?
（李牧(りぼく)）蒙驁本軍は城３つ
こちらの副将は城５つ
The Meng Ao Main Army has taken three castles.
This Vice General has taken five castles.
そして…
And...
this makes the eighth castle for the other Vice General.
もう１人の副将は これで城８つ目
E-Eight?!
（文官）や… ８つ
（文官）この短期間で…
In this short a period?!
The strength of the Meng Ao Army is just as predicted...
蒙驁軍の戦力は予想どおり
ですが 副将たちの強さは
予想の上を行っている
But the strength of the two Vice Generals is far greater.
How did I completely overlook these two?
なぜか
この存在は完全に見落としていた…
Just what are they...?
この２人は 一体…
Wang Ben
L-Lord Li Mu...
（文官）り… 李牧どの…
（李牧）マズイですね
This is quite bad.
If the State of Qin is able to do such a thing as capturing Shanyang,
もし秦国が
山陽を取るようなことがあれば―
the State of Qin will obtain a great foothold to entering central China.
秦国は 中華の中央へ出る
大きな足がかりを手にしてしまう
Normally, we, the State of Zhao would try to prevent this
本来なら
我ら趙国は これを阻止すべく―
魏国に援軍を送るところですが
by sending reinforcements to the State of Wei.
But with the alliance in place, we cannot do that.
同盟がジャマをして
それも かないません
Was it Changpingjun that constructed this grand scheme of attacking Shanyang?
（李牧）山陽攻略という大戦略を
立てたのは あの昌平君ですか…
Just what I would expect from him, a big move that he can only launch at this moment.
さすがに
今しかできない大きな一手を―
打ってきましたね
Urgent report!
（伝者Ｂ）
急報！ 廉頗将軍は山陽城を通過！
General Lian Po has just passed Shanyang Caslte!
Passed?!
（文官）通過！
（文官）入城しなかったのか！
He didn't enter the castle?!
（文官）では 野戦か？
Then they're going to battle on the plains?
Incredible. It's just as Lord Li Mu predicted.
（カイネ）
すごい… 李牧さまの読みどおりだ
It seems General Lian Po is confident, of course.
（李牧）さすがに
廉頗将軍は自信があるようです
I suppose we'll just have to watch over the events and hope for General Lian Po's victory.
こうなったら
廉頗将軍の勝ちを祈って―
戦いを見守りましょう
Will we all be okay?
（カイネ）大丈夫でしょうか？
I would place the State of Wei Army's chance of victory at eight or nine out of ten.
（李牧）
十中八九 魏国軍の勝ちです
何しろ 今でも
あの方に正面から勝てる武将は―
Even now, there's not a single military commander in the world, including me, that can win against that man head on.
私を含めて
天下に１人もいませんからね
( Flags - Lian )
It has been about two months now since the State of Qin Army started its invasion of the State of Wei.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）秦国軍が魏国に
侵攻を開始してより およそ２か月
ついに廉頗は この戦いの
決戦の地 山陽に到着した
And now, Lian Po has finally reached the land of the decisive battle, Shanyang.
だが 廉頗が この地の野戦で―
But the reason why Lian Po was not able to take full advantage of encamping on all of the mountains in this area
最も利のある満山(まんざん)に
布陣しなかったのは…
was because the State of Qin Vice Generals were already stationed there.
既に 秦国軍の副将が
布陣していたからである
（廉頗）フッ…
まずは合格点をやろうかのぅ
I'll give you a passing grade for now.
（昂(こう)）あっ 虎！ 虎だ！
Look, a tiger!
Hey, Xin! Weren't you saying you wanted to see a tiger?!
ほら 信！
虎 見たいって言ってただろう！
（尾平）うるせえ！
（昂）あいて！
Shut up!
Are you an idiot?
バカか お前！
信たちのジャマすんじゃねえよ！
Don't bother Xin and the others.
今 あの４人は―
Right now, those four are
considering how the Feixin Unit should fight now that it has a thousand people.
1,000になった飛信隊の戦い方を
考えてんだから
（中鉄(ちゅうてつ)）ンッ…
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）それで 第３隊を右に２つ
Then, move the third unit two to the right.
Zhong Tie, two to the right.
中鉄 ２コ右だ
（中鉄）ンッ…
（信）そっちは左だ
That's the left.
こっちから見て 右！
Right from where I'm looking!
３コじゃねえ ２コだ
Two, not three!
だから そっちは左だって！
I just said, that's the left!
And then if the first unit circles around, we'll win. Probably.
（羌瘣）
そして 第１隊が回り込めば勝ち
多分
L-Lord Qiang Lei, where did you study the art of war?
（楚水）きょ… 羌瘣どのは
一体 どこで兵法の勉強を？
Study?
（羌瘣）勉強？ 別に
Nowhere. I just came up with that just now. It seemed right.
今考えただけ 適当に
S-So you're a natural at it?
て… 天才というやつですか…
ハハハハッ！ すげえだろう 羌瘣は
Ain't Qiang Lei awesome?
でも 剣抜いたときのほうが
もっと すげえぞ
But he's even more impressive when he takes out his sword!
You'll be glad he's your ally, then!
味方で良かったと思うこと
間違いなし
ウワッ！
アハハッ… まあ こんな感じか
Okay, well something like this, then.
Let's try to gradually think up some more strategies, too.
ほかの作戦も
おいおい考えていこうや
General Lian Po!
（伝者Ｂ）廉頗さま！ 秦国軍
今ひとりの副将が留山(りゅうざん)に到着
One of the Vice Generals of the State of Qin Army has reached Mount Liu!
布陣したもようです
（部下Ａ）留山に？
It seems he's made an encampment there!
At Mount Liu?!
Why would he do that?
（部下Ａ）どういうことだ？
That mountain is far off and away from the predicted main battleground.
あの山は
予定している主戦場からは程遠いぞ
（部下Ｂ）
さては 場所を見誤ったか？
Did he just mistake where he was? Or is he just intimidated?!
それとも おじけづいたか！
（廉頗）フン… わざとであれば
相当クセの強い武将のようじゃのぅ
If that was on purpose, then he seems to be a general with particularly strong idiosyncrasies.
Taking a distance is used frequently by strategists that like change.
（姜燕(きょうえん)）距離を取るのは
変化を好む軍略家に多いですから
どこぞの変幻自在じじいと
同じにおいがするのぅ ハハハッ…
Smells a lot like a certain ever-changing old man.
それで？
蒙驁の本軍は どうなっておる？
So, what is going on with Meng Ao's headquarters?
They are currently at a place called Xiang.
（部下Ｂ）現在 郷(ごう)の地
到着は明日と思われます
We believe they will arrive tomorrow.
We believe our armies will be assembled tomorrow as well, yes?
（介子坊(かいしぼう)）こちらの全軍が
そろうのも明日でしょう
In other words, the battle starts tomorrow!
つまり 開戦は明日以降
ハハハハッ！ 酒じゃ！
Get some booze!
A pre-victory celebration!
勝利の前祝いじゃ！
全兵士に酒を与えよ！
Liquor for all soldiers!
（蒙驁）明日か…
Tomorrow, eh?
（兵士）どっちも頑張れ！
Go for it!
Go!
（尾平）用意… 始め！
Ready... go!
（沛浪(はいろう)）ンンッ！
You bastard, don't head butt me!
（田永）
てめえ 頭突きしてんじゃねえ
ぶっ飛ばすぞ！
I'll beat the shit outta you!
（沛浪）
うるせえ！ てめえだろうが！
Sheddep, so did you!
What'd you say?!
（田永）なんだと こら！
（沛浪）ああ？
Geez, you're both disqualified!
ダーッ！ 両者 失格！
What was that?!
（沛浪･田永）なんだと てめえ！
What idiots!
（信）バッカでえ ハハッ！
Ready... go!
用意… 始め！
（兵士）すげえぞ 竜川！
（兵士）やれやれ！
よっしゃ！ 勝負だ 竜川
（竜川）えっ？ で… でも…
All right, you're on, Long Chuan!
B-But..
いったれ 竜川！
隊長だろうと関係ねえぞ
Just do it, Long Chuan!
Forget that he's the captain!
Just don't get hurt, Captain!
（崇原(すうげん)）ケガだけは するなよ 隊長
But... the difference in strength between the captain and me is too big.
（竜川）これは…
隊長と おいらじゃ
力の差がありすぎる
ど… どうしよう？
本当に あっさり勝っちゃったら
What do I do?
If I really do just win easily...
（尾平）始め！
（信）アアーッ！
Go!
What was that, Xin?!
なんだよ 信！
隊長のくせに情けねえ
That was pathetic! You're supposed to be the captain!
カス！ アホ！ バ～カ！
（信の泣き声）
You piece of crap! Moron! Loser!
That's our Long Chuan.
（崇原）さすが竜川だぜ
こりゃ
竜川が隊長でいいんじゃないか？
Maybe Long Chuan should be the captain?!
（竜有(りゅうゆう)）
そうだ そうだ　竜川隊長！
Yeah, yeah!
Captain Long Chuan!
（兵士たち）
竜川隊長！ 竜川隊長！ 竜川隊長！
Captain Long Chuan! Captain Long Chuan! Captain Long Chuan!
（竜川）悪くない
Not bad.
Okay. Ready...
（尾平）いくぞ！ 用意…
Piao told me...
（信）漂(ひょう)が言ってたな
力比べってのは
単純な怪力勝負じゃねえ
Strength tests like these aren't just about a match of who's the brawniest.
コツがあるんだって
There are skills to them.
First, when you grab hands, you subtlety make it seem like you're not that strong.
まず 手を組んだときに
バレない程度に力を弱く見せといて
And the moment it starts, you use every joint in your body
開始の瞬間 全身の関節を駆使し
to focus the strength of every muscle in your body to your right arm like this
全筋肉の力を
この右腕に向かって―
and make it explode!
爆発させる！
始め！
（信）ドリャー！
Go!
（信）よっしゃー！
（歓声）
（田有(でんゆう)）ウオーッ！ すげえぞ 信
（昂）やっぱ 隊長だ！
That was awesome, Xin!
I knew the captain could do it!
Captain Xin! Captain Xin! Captain Xin!
（兵士たち）信隊長！ 信隊長！
（信）ヘヘヘッ… どうだ！
What's up, Qiang Lei?
（信）どうした？ 羌瘣
（羌瘣）信 少しだけいいか？
Xin, could I have a moment with you?
There's something I want to talk about.
話したいことがある
（信）うん？
私は地に足が着いていない
My... feet do not reach the ground.
Because of that, I cannot move forward like all of you.
だから お前たちみたいに
前に進めていない
I really think that's because I still
haven't avenged Big Sis Xiang.
それは やっぱり
象(しょう)姉の敵(かたき)を討ってないからだ
I still vividly remember the pain from that day.
あのときの痛みは
今でも はっきり覚えている
But...
だけど…
I'm putting off avenging Big Sis Xiang by staying at a place like this.
私は
その象姉の敵討ちを後回しにして
こんな所にいる
And I'm sure that's because... this place is...
それは きっと ここが…
the only place I can call home now.
ここが 今の私にとって
唯一の帰る場所だからだ
Xin,
信…
（信）うん？
it's like you said before, my path will still continue after I get revenge.
以前 お前が言ったように
敵討ちの先には 道が続いている
If I don't, Big Sis Xiang would never by happy after all the time we spent dreaming of the outside world.
じゃないと 外を夢みていた象姉も
浮かばれないし
And... I want that myself, too.
私自身も そう願っている
But right now, my path is moving towards avenging Big Sis Xiang.
でも やっぱり 私のその道は―
象姉の敵討ちの先に
広がっているんだ
So...
だから…
So when this war is over, I'm leaving here.
だから この戦が終わったら
私は ここを出ていく
I don't know how many months or years it'll take...
何か月…
何年かかるか分からないけど…
but I'll make sure I get my revenge.
きっちり敵を討つ
And when that's done, if I come back again...
そして それが終わって
また帰ってきたら…
そのときは―
When that happens, I think I'll really be able to move forward with all of you.
私も ちゃんと
お前たちと一緒に前に進めると思う
No objections here!
異論なし！
（羌瘣）ウワッ…
ヘヘッ… 本当は俺も―
Honestly, I've been thinking for a while that that's what you should do.
ちょっと前から お前は
そうすべきじゃねえかと思ってた
When you said you had something to talk to me about,
話があるっつうから
今すぐ抜けるのかと焦ったけどな
I got nervous because I thought you were gonna leave right now.
I'll leave once I've completed my work.
仕事は きっちり済ませていく
（信）ひとまず
この戦が お前の置き土産だな
So this war is kind of a parting gift to you, huh?
Let's win, Qiang Lei!
勝とうぜ 羌瘣
Right.
And hey, you know, you are pretty cute.
（信）…つうか お前
やっぱ かわいいんだな 笑うと特に
Especially when you smile.
This is an order to all units from General Tu Men!
（土門(どもん)）
将軍 土門より全軍に通達する！
The First Camp of the State of Wei Army
（土門）
本攻略の最終目的地 山陽に―
既に 魏国軍の第１陣と
秦国軍副将が到着した
and the State of Qin Army Vice Generals have already
reached the final destination of our main attack, Shanyang!
Both armies are staring each other down as they wait for allies!
両軍は にらみ合ったまま
友軍の到着を待っている
魏国軍は続々と集結中！
The State of Wei Army is now gathering one group after another!
But we will not be outdone!
我らも
後れを取るわけにはいかぬ！
All units, forward march!
全軍 行軍の足を進めよ！
決戦の時は近いぞ！
The decisive moment approaches!
進めー！
Forward!
（信）ヘヘッ…
らしくなってきやがったぜ
Now that's more like it.
Yes.
All right!
よっしゃ！ いくぜ 飛信隊！
Let's go, Feixin Unit!
Preview
Clash!
End